KARTIK B BHARGAV

Software Engineer and Data Science Enthusiast

+31 626928158 | kartikbhargav93@gmail.com | Pisanostraat 140, 5623CE Eindhoven, Netherlands https://www.linkedin.com/in/kartik-b-bhargav

BIO

I am an ambitious and driven software engineer and a seasoned software developer with over six years of experience in developing enterprise software applications seeking full time roles as **Python Developer**. I am also a graduate in Data Science from **Eindhoven University of Technology**.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Rabobank, Software Engineer, Utrecht, The Netherlands

Dec 2022 - Nov 2023

- Implemented Azure durable functions required to categorize transactions in real time streaming setup using Python.
- Implemented the core orchestrator logic to categorize real time transactions using Python and Kafka in Azure Cloud.
- Created a **dashboard** in **Azure Application Insights** using **KQL** to monitor the operational metrics of the Transaction Categorization Engine.
- Setup a local testing environment to test the entire architecture of transaction categorization engine using **Docker**, **FastAPI** and **PostgreSQL** which in turn significantly sped up the development process of the team.
- Performed ETL and Exploratory Data Analysis using Databricks to resolve customer facing issues.

TomTom, Data Software Engineer, Eindhoven, The Netherlands

May 2022 - Nov 2022

- Performed benchmarking and evaluated the behavior of the map comparison tool for different noise levels using
 Python and Numpy.
- Performed Exploratory Data Analysis of various map datasets using Python, GeoPandas and QGIS.
- Improved the speed of the map comparison tool by 300% by configuring the code to run in a PyPy environment.
- Increased the **code coverage** of the map comparison tool by adding new unit test cases using **Pytest** and visualized the various map sources in the test scenarios using **Matplotlib**.

TNO, Graduate Thesis Intern, Helmond, The Netherlands

May 2021 - Oct 2021

- Performed data cleaning, data pre-processing, exploratory data analysis and feature engineering on the battery degradation dataset provided by TNO.
- Implemented Support Vector Regression, LSTM model and Instance based Learning model to predict the remaining useful life of lithium-ion batteries for electric vehicles using Python and MATLAB.
- Communicated and presented the results to multiple stakeholders within the organization.

VMWare, Member of Technical Staff, Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Oct 2017 - Jun 2019

- Implemented the complete server side code to support device management of Linux devices in the VMWare Workspace ONE UEM console using MSSQL, Python and C#.
- Taught **Git** and writing integration tests using **SpecFlow** to a team of 15 Quality Engineers as part of testing team migration from manual testing to automation testing.
- Implemented a pipeline to automatically execute the **unit tests** on the Airwatch Windows Mobile Agent application and generate test case execution report for every build triggered on the build server using **Python**.

VMWare AirWatch, Member of Technical Staff, Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Jul 2015 - Oct 2017

- Achieved a reduction of 50% in the memory size of Airwatch Windows Mobile Agent using C++.
- Implemented multiple proof of concepts (POCs) for the Airwatch Windows Mobile Agent application using Python and C++.
- Fixed multiple bugs and handled customer escalations in the source code of Airwatch Windows Mobile Agent using **Python** and **C++**.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Communications

Sri Jayacharamarajendra College of Engineering

Sep 2011 – May 2015 Mysuru, Karnataka, India

PROJECTS

Image Caption Generation @ TU Eindhoven

Apr 2020 - Apr 2020

Implemented a LSTM network which takes an image representation obtained from a CNN as input and produces a caption
describing the image for the Flickr8k dataset using Keras.

High performance implementation of Leave One Out Cross Validation @ TU Eindhoven

Feb 2020 - Mar 2020

 Implemented a high performance code for Leave One Out Cross Validation (LOOCV) on the MNIST dataset using NumPy which runs on multiple cores available in the system. This reduced the computation time up to 80%.

World Development Indicators Visualization @ TU Eindhoven

Nov 2019 - Dec 2019

 Implemented the dashboards using Tableau to perform a visual analysis of the population characteristics and carbon footprints of various countries across the globe.

SKILLS

Programming Skills: Python, C++, C#, C, Rust, MSSQL, PostgreSQL, Typescript

Software: PyCharm, Jupyter, Google Colab, IntelliJ, Visual Studio, VSCode, SQL Server Studio, Powerpoint, ProM

Data Science: TensorFlow, Scikit-Learn, Process Mining, XGBoost, Keras, Pandas, Numpy, Scipy, Excel

Methodologies: Agile (Scrum), Waterfall, CI/CD, DevOps

Deployment : Docker, Kubernetes, Git, Azure DevOps, GitHub, Gitlab, Bitbucket, Jira

Visualization: Tableau, PowerBI, Google Data Studio, Matplotlib, Plotly Dash

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux (Ubuntu), MacOS

Python Libraries: FastAPI, Falcon, SQLAlchemy, Poetry, Pydantic

COURSES AND CERTIFICATIONS

Advanced NLP with SpaCy	Datacamp - Apr 2021
Crash Course on Python by Google	Coursera - Sep 2020
Introduction to Git and Github by Google	Coursera - Aug 2020
Data Scientist Nanodegree - Term 1 by Google	Udacity - Mar 2019
Introduction to Data Science in Python by Google	Coursera - Apr 2017
A Crash Course in Data Science by John Hopkins University	Coursera - Jan 2016
Python for Everybody Specialization by University of Michigan	Coursera - Oct 2015

LANGUAGES

English – Professional Working Proficiency Kannada – Native or Bilingual Proficiency Hindi – Limited Working Proficiency

HONORS AND AWARDS

Top 10% in the Workation Price Prediction Challenge ML Hackathon in MachineHack.	Feb 2021
Awarded Amandus H. Lundqvist Scholarship and Holland Scholarship from TU Eindhoven (TU/e).	Aug 2019
Recognized as the Best performing team member at VMware.	Apr 2019
Won the Best Paper Presenter award in the international conference ICEECCOT-2018 held at GSSSIETW, Mysuru.	Dec 2018

INTERESTS

Tech - Web Scraping, Android App Development, Embedded Programming **Sports** – Badminton, Cycling, Chess **Arts** - Listening to Music, Singing